Valerio Lanziani

Curriculum Vitae

Via della Torre, 9 01030 Bassano in Teverina, VT ℘ (+39) 347 112 8343 ⋈ valerio.lanziani@gmail.com

Summary

Full stack developer currently working on large scale web apps. Strong experience with React.js, Sass, Node and GraphQL. Great knowledge of JavaScript, Java and C++ programming languages. My career also comprises in-depth looks on both non-relational and relational databases and the AWS Stack.

Strong willingness to constantly learn and improve. Always open to take on new visions and challenges.

Experience

2018 - Now Lead front-end developer, APPLAUDART, Viterbo.

Currently working on the company's flagship product using React.js, Node, GraphQL and the AWS framework. My main responsibilities include the design and implementation of critical features from the UI to the business logic on the front-end side, co-leading the development department and tutoring of junior developers. Among the technologies I use daily there are Redux, React Router, Apollo GraphQL, Amazon's DynamoDB, ElasticSearch and AWS AppSync.

2015 - 2018 Full stack developer, INTECS, Rome.

Worked as consultant on multiple projects focused on the management, analysis and processing of military data through a multi-tier architecture. In that time I helped designing and implementing user interfaces, business logic, microservices and APIs. Some of the utilized technologies were Qt framework, OracleDB, Spring framework, RabbitMQ, Apache Maven and Jenkins.

2014 - 2015 Back-end developer, TRANSLATED, Rome.

During my time in Translated, I was tasked on designing and implementing their first graph database, aiming on improving search results and overall performances. Other duties comprised the smart import and export of billions of records, development of the APIs and service layers and integration of the new features in the front-end side. Main technologies were OrientDB, Neo4j, Redis, MySQL and Apache ActiveMQ.

Education

2015 **Master's Degree in Computer Engineering**, Roma Tre University, Rome.

Graph-oriented extension on the Translation Memories' model in the translation industry

2012 **Bachelor's Degree in Computer Engineering**, Roma Tre University, Rome. Visualization system of urban public transportation on maps

Skills (sorted by experience)

OS Linux, Windows, OS X

Languages Javascript, GraphQL, Java, C++, PHP, Python

Frameworks React, Node, AWS Stack, Spring, Apache ActiveMQ, RabbitMQ

Databases OrientDB, Neo4j, OracleDB, MySQL, Redis

Tools Git, Maven, Jenkins

Languages

Italian Mothertongue

English Professional working proficiency